<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>HSCIC on this is rob dyke dot com</title>
    <link>https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/tags/hscic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HSCIC on this is rob dyke dot com</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://robdyke.com/rdprofile.jpg</url>
      <link>https://robdyke.com/rdprofile.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 13:09:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/tags/hscic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Community and Governance</title>
      <link>https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/posts/2013/2013-11-14-community-and-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 13:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/posts/2013/2013-11-14-community-and-governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the second in a short series of posts where I&amp;rsquo;m looking at the announcements from NHS England / HSCIC in support of open source solutions for NHS organisations. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m looking at the role of governance and community around open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the Safer Hospitals, Safer Wards Technology Fund announced in June of this year, &lt;a href=&#34;http://garymcallisteronline.blogspot.co.uk/2013/07/open-source-in-nhs.html&#34;&gt;Gary McAllister posted a comment piece&lt;/a&gt; which neatly summarises key criteria of open source which I paraphrase here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The code should be freely available online, well-documented and accessible. It should be evident from the code repository that regular commits are made to the project from multiple sources, demonstrating that the code-base is active.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The licensing for the code should utilise an &amp;ldquo;Open&amp;rdquo; license. Examples of licenses which meet the Open Source Initiative definition of open source can be seen here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A project should have corporate investment and a viable service provider clearly backing the product. This may sound counter intuitive but in order for an Open solution to be viable long-term it needs backing from a corporate entity. Without corporate backing the solution is &amp;ldquo;unsupported&amp;rdquo; and there is little evidence to ensure continued development. You could end up with a stale loaf of bread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levelling the playing field and educating the customer</title>
      <link>https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/posts/2013/2013-11-12-levelling-the-playing-field-educating-the-customer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 11:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/posts/2013/2013-11-12-levelling-the-playing-field-educating-the-customer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There have been several announcements from NHS England / HSCIC in support of open source solutions for NHS organisations. These announcements have spawned much discussion and debate - on EHI/HSJ/NHSHackday sites and at EHILive - which ranges in style and content from Chicken Licken to Richard Stallman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a short series of blogs I&amp;rsquo;m planning to post I&amp;rsquo;m going to look at these announcements and the reaction from a few different perspectives. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m looking at where the direction for such support from NHS England is coming from and what &amp;lsquo;support&amp;rsquo; for open source solutions might actually mean.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dissecting a major Govt IT project to deliver a political objective</title>
      <link>https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/posts/2013/2013-11-05-dissecting-a-major-govt-it-project-to-deliver-a-political-objective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 17:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robdyke.com/h2r2d2/posts/2013/2013-11-05-dissecting-a-major-govt-it-project-to-deliver-a-political-objective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes taken on observing people the other side of the pond dissecting a major Govt IT project to deliver a political objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would this project have benefited from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-10-16/open-source-everything-the-moral-of-the-healthcare-dot-gov-debacle&#34;&gt;Opensorcery&lt;/a&gt;? If PPACA wasn&amp;rsquo;t communist enough! Writing in Bloomberg Businessweek, Paul Ford explains that the debacle known as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.healthcare.gov/&#34;&gt;healthcare.gov&lt;/a&gt; makes clear that it is time for government to change the way it delivers IT: embrace the open source approach to software development that has revolutionized the technology industry. Well, openness worked before for Obama e.g. with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itdashboard.gov/&#34;&gt;IT spending dashboard&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/it-dashboard/&#34;&gt;code here&lt;/a&gt;) but that was in the first years of the first term. You can do &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt; in that period of a presidency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the Congressional hearing (which makes our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201314/cmselect/cmpubacc/294/29402.htm&#34;&gt;PAC look rather tame on NPfIT&lt;/a&gt;) as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/oct/24/obamacare-website-testify-congress-live&#34;&gt;reported by Grauniad&lt;/a&gt; two lessons stand out for me. One technical, the other political.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a technical perspective the importance of proving an end-to-end test FIRST and n&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SuzyKhimm/statuses/393392886965747712&#34;&gt;ot two weeks prior to a go-live&lt;/a&gt; is crucial. This is the approach we are taking with Wardware and the other projects we are working on. Can we pass a simple message through the components of the stack? No. Fix it. And now? Yes. Great! Build on and test for regressions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
